Guide to the Fred Friendly Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Conferences and Seminars, 1962-1996
  - Publishing in the Next Millennium, 1987 May 3 (Box 163, Folder F.8)
  - Quality and Cost Forum, 1987 April 26 (Box 163, Folder F.9)
  - The Question Why --BBC Program, 1972 (Box 163, Folder F.10)
  - Radio Television News Directors Association, 1962-1965 (Box 163, Folder F.11)
  - Rebuilding Urban America, 1988 October 24 (Box 163, Folder F.12)
  - Re-examining Values: Society in Transition, 1991 March 5 (Box 163, Folder F.13)
  - Reporting on the Courts and the Law, 1991 October 4 (Box 163, Folder F.14)
  - The Right to Privacy: A Socratic Dialogue, 1991 October 24 (Box 163, Folder F.15)
  - The Role of Judiciary in a Modern Democracy, 1987 August 10 (Box 163, Folder F.16)
  - San Diego Forum on Ethics, 1988 December 6 (Box 163, Folder F.17)
  - A Scenario in Ethics, 1986-1991 (Box 164, Folder F.1)
  - Science Week Project, 1995 December 16 (Box 164, Folder F.2)
  - Search and Seizure, 1986 June 2 (Box 164, Folder F.3)
  - Senior Symposium: Applying Ethical Principles, 1986 April 12 (Box 164, Folder F.4)
  - Seventh Edinburgh International Television Festival, 1982 (Box 164, Folder F.5)
  - Shaping Tomorrow's Workforce, 1988 September 26 (Box 164, Folder F.6)
  - Social Responsibility of the Mass Media, 1969 November 19 (Box 164, Folder F.7)
  - Society of Christian Ethics, 1986 January 17 (Box 164, Folder F.8)
  - Society for College and University Planning, 1991 July 15 (Box 164, Folder F.9)
  - Socratic Dialogue, 1985-1989 (Box 164, Folder F.10)
  - Sounds of Change, 1988 June 22 (Box 164, Folder F.11)
  - Special Advertising Sections, 1984 (Box 164, Folder F.12)
  - Spoils, Ethics and the Washington Way of Life, 1990 March 5 (Box 164, Folder F.13)
  - Spoils, Ethics and the Washington Way of Life, 1990 March 5 (Box 165, Folder F.1)
  - Substance Abuse, 1989 (Box 165, Folder F.2)
  - Telecourse Conference, 1988 (Box 165, Folder F.3)
  - Television: the Power of the Media, 1986 November 22 (Box 165, Folder F.4)
  - Terrorism and the News Media: The Beirut Hostage Crisis, 1985 October 18 (Box 165, Folder F.5)
  - Dick Thornburgh/Harris Wofford Debate, 1991 (Box 165, Folder F.6)
  - Through the Learning Glass, 1992 April 10 (Box 165, Folder F.7)
  - Trustee Retreat (Seminar on Higher Education), 1991 October 11 (Box 165, Folder F.8)
  - The Two Worlds of the Campus Journalist, 1985 (Box 165, Folder F.9)
  - The U.S. Constitution: Assuring Continuity through Controversy, 1987 June 1 (Box 165, Folder F.10)
  - United States District Court Judicial Conference, 1988 March 31 (Box 165, Folder F.11)
  - UNCF Citicorp Fellows Program, 1989 (Box 165, Folder F.12)
  - U.S. Television News (Seminars in Contemporary American Studies), 1981 July 10 (Box 165, Folder F.13)
  - Values and Visions (Hospital Ethics), 1986 May 22 (Box 165, Folder F.14)
  - Voluntary Hospital of America Panel, 1989 (Box 165, Folder F.15)
  - Window on the World: History of World Television --Proposal, 1982 (Box 166, Folder F.1)
  - Women at the Crossroads, 1989 October 11 (Box 166, Folder F.2)
  - Worldwide Marketing Seminar for Campbell Soup Company, 1986 October 15 (Box 166, Folder F.3)
  - Contracts and Programs for Other Seminars, 1981-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder F.4-5)
- Series V: Television and Radio, 1947-1991
  This series contains a small but varied representation of Friendly's career as an announcer, from his early work as a writer and announcer for WEAN-Providence though his time as president of CBS. Materials include scripts and transcripts of programs with related notes, office correspondence and memos, and research notes.
  - Subseries V.1: CBS, 1947-1991
    This subseries holds scripts, transcripts, and related notes for radio programs I Can Hear it Now: 1933-1945 and I Can Hear it Now: the 1960s, and episodes of the television programs See It Now, CBS Reports, CBS News Specials, and several stand alone programs. It also contains a small amount of correspondence about the production of programs and clippings, articles, and correspondence concerning to Edward R. Murrow.
    - CBS Radio (Box 166)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 166, Folder F.6)
      - CBS News Ten-Minute Hourly Radio--Script, circa 1968 (Box 166, Folder F.7)
      - Quote, Unquote
        - Audition Script, 1947 October 13 (Box 166, Folder F.8)
        - Transcript, 1947 (Box 166, Folder F.9)
      - "This is Edward R. Murrow"--Script, 1965 April 30 (Box 166, Folder F.10)
      - "WCBS Looks at Television," 1966 March 25 (Folder F.11)
        - "1933-1945"--Script Drafts, circa 1948, (9 Folders) (Box 167)
        - "1933-1945"--Script Drafts, circa 1948 (Box 168, Folder F.1)
        - Clippings, 1948-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 168, Folder F.2-3)
        - Contracts, 1950-1951 (Box 168, Folder F.4)
        - "1960s"--Outline and Notes, 1970 (Box 168, Folder F.5)
        - "1960s"--Script Drafts, circa 1970, (5 Folders) (Box 168, Folder F.6-10)
        - "1960s"--Script Drafts, circa 1970, (8 Folders) (Box 169, Folder F.1-8)
        - "1960s"--Script Drafts, circa 1970, (2 Folders) (Box 170, Folder F.1-2)
        - Research Notes and Memos, 1970s (Box 170, Folder F.3)
    - CBS TV
      - General
        - Thursday News with Fred Friendly--Introduction by Richard Salant, undated (Box 170, Folder F.4)
        - Correspondence and Memos, 1961-1972, (2 Folders) (Box 170, Folder F.5-6)
        - Resignation, 1966 (Box 170, Folder F.7)
        - List of Documentaries Produced by CBS, 1966-1973 (Box 170, Folder F.8)
      - Individual Program Episodes (Box 171)
        - "CBS Building Show"--Transcript, 1966 July 9 (Box 171, Folder F.1)
        - "Conversation with President Kennedy"--Transcript, 1962 December 17 (Box 171, Folder F.2)
        - Face the Nation--Transcript, 1969 September 14 (Box 171, Folder F.3)
        - "An Hour with Ed Murrow"--Transcript, 1965 April 30 (Box 171, Folder F.4)
        - "The Senate and the Watergate Affair"--Transcript and Research Notes, 1973 May 13, (2 Folders) (Box 171, Folder F.5-6)
        - "Small World"--List of Panels, 1959 (Box 171, Folder F.7)
        - Vietnam News Coverage--Attack on Cam Ne--Correspondence, 1965 (Box 171, Folder F.8)
        - Vietnam News Coverage--Correspondence, 1965 (Box 171, Folder F.9)
        - VIETMAN PERSPECTIVE: "The Congress and the War"--Transcript, 1966 January 30 (Box 171, Folder F.10)
        - "Watching the Watchdog"--Transcript, 1981 April 20 (Box 171, Folder F.11)
        - Show Schedules, 1951-1957 (Box 171)
        - Clippings, 1954-1982 (Box 171, Folder 1F.3)
        - Draft of Series Introduction, circa 1954 (Box 171, Folder F.14)
        - Friendly's thoughts on SEE IT NOW, undated (Box 171, Folder F.15)
        - Churchill--Transcript, undated (Box 171, Folder F.16)
        - "Conversation with J. Robert Oppenheimer"--Transcript, 1955 January 4 (Box 171, Folder F.17)
        - Egypt and Israel--Transcript and Notes, 1956 March 13 (Box 171, Folder F.18)
        - "The Farm Problem"--Transcript, 1956 January 26 (Box 172, Folder F.1)
        - Joseph McCarthy Program
          - Clippings, 1956-1968 (Box 172, Folder F.2)
          - Transcript, 1954 March 9 (Box 172, Folder F.3)
          - Correspondence and Press Statements, 1954 March-April (Box 172, Folder F.4)
          - Draft of "The Senator and the Broadcaster," by Joseph Wershba, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder F.5-6)
          - Rebuttal Program--Transcript, 1954 April 6 (Box 172, Folder F.7)
        - New York City Philharmonic--Transcript, 1954 March 2 (Box 172, Folder F.8)
        - Satchmo Program--Draft of Program Introduction, undated (Box 172, Folder F.9)
        - "The Secret Life of Danny Kaye"--Transcript, 1957 December 2 (Box 172, Folder F.10)
        - "Statehood for Alaska and Hawaii"--Transcript, 1958 March 2 (Box 172, Folder F.11)
        - "Sweating Out Christmas in Korea"--Transcript, 1952 December 10 (Box 172, Folder F.12)
        - "The Vice Presidency"--Transcript, 1955 (Box 172, Folder F.13)
        - "Victory at Thermopylae"--Transcript, 1955 June 28 (Box 172, Folder F.14)
      - "Business and the Press," 1982 December 25 (Box 173)
      - "A Conversation with Henry Kissinger," 1973 February 1 (Box 173, Folder F.2)
      - "The Coverage of Terror," undated (Box 173, Folder F.3)
      - "Justice Black and the Bill of Rights," 1971 July 20 (Box 173, Folder F.4)
      - "Private Lives, Public Press," 1983 April 11 (Box 173, Folder F.5)
      - CBS Reports, 1959-1964--booklet, 1964 (Box 173)
      - Transcripts
        - "109 Days to Venus," 1962 December 12 (Box 173, Folder F.7)
        - "Abortion and the Law," 1965 April 5 (Box 173, Folder F.8)
        - "Barry Goldwater-The View from the Right," 1962 March 3 (Box 173, Folder F.9)
        - "The Beat Majority and the Supreme Court," 1962 March 29 (Box 173, Folder F.10)
        - "Berlin: End of the Line," 1960 June 17 (Box 173, Folder F.11)
        - "Biography of a Bookie Joint," 1961-1963 (Box 173, Folder F.12)
        - "Biography of a Cancer," 1960 April 21 (Box 173, Folder F.13)
        - "Biography of a Missile," 1959 October 27 (Box 173, Folder F.14)
        - "Birth Control and the Law," 1963 May 29 (Box 173, Folder F.15)
        - "Brazil: The Rude Awakening," 1961 November 2 (Box 173, Folder F.16)
        - "Breaking the Trade Barrier," 1962 May 24 (Box 173, Folder F.17)
        - "Britain: Blood, Sweat and Tears Plus 20," 1961 March 30 (Box 173, Folder F.18)
        - "Bulldozed America," 1965 September 14 (Box 173, Folder F.19)
        - "The Business of Health: Medicine, Money and Politics," 1961 February 2 (Box 173, Folder F.20)
        - "The Business of Heroin," 1964 January 22 (Box 173, Folder F.21)
        - "The California Battleground: Nixon vs. Brown," 1962 October 31 (Box 173, Folder F.22)
        - "Can We Disarm?" 1961 December 14 (Box 174, Folder F.1)
        - "Carl Sandburg at Gettysburg," 1961 April 13 (Box 174, Folder F.2)
        - "The Case of the Boston Electra," 1961 February 16 (Box 174, Folder F.3)
        - "Case History of a Rumor," 1963 November 13 (Box 174, Folder F.4)
        - "The Catholics and the Schools," 1964 February 5 (Box 174, Folder F.5)
        - "Cigarettes: A Collision of Interests," 1964 April 15 (Box 174, Folder F.6)
        - "The Crisis of Presidential Succession," 1964 January 8 (Box 174, Folder F.7)
        - "Crossroads Africa: Pilot for a Peace Corps," 1961 March 16 (Box 174, Folder F.8)
        - "D-Day Plus 20 Years: Eisenhower Returns to Normandy," 1964 June 5, (2 Folders) (Box 174, Folder F.9-10)
        - "Deadlock: The Railroad Dispute," 1963 June 12 (Box 174, Folder F.11)
        - "Death In the City Room," 1962 January 25 (Box 174, Folder F.12)
        - "DeGaulle: The Challenge," 1964 May 6 (Box 174, Folder F.13)
        - "DeGaulle: Roots of Power," 1964 April 29 (Box 174, Folder F.14)
        - "The Divorce Dilemma," 1966 February 15 (Box 174, Folder F.15)
        - "East Europe: Satellites Out of Orbit," 1965 February 8 (Box 174, Folder F.16)
        - "The Education of George Waruhiu," 1964 June 24 (Box 174, Folder F.17)
        - "Eisenhower,"1963 January 23 (Box 174, Folder F.18)
        - "The Fat American," 1962 January 18 (Box 174, Folder F.19)
        - "Filibuster-Birth Struggle of a Law," 1964 March 18 (Box 174, Folder F.20)
        - "The Flight from Hollywood," 1964 February 19 (Box 174, Folder F.21)
        - "Germany Since Hitler: Adenauer Sums Up," 1963 February 6 (Box 174, Folder F.22)
        - "Gideon's Trumpet: The Poor Man and the Law," 1964 October 7 (Box 174, Folder F.23)
        - "The Great American Funeral," 1963 October 23 (Box 175, Folder F.1)
        - "The Great Holiday Massacre," 1960 December 26 (Box 175, Folder F.2)
        - "The Harlem Temper," 1963-1964 (Box 175, Folder F.3)
        - "Harvest of Shame," 1960 November 25 (Box 175, Folder F.4)
        - "The Hidden Face of Poverty" and "Death of a Navy Yard," 1965 January 4 (Box 175, Folder F.5)
        - "The Hot and Cold Wars of Allen Dulles," 1962 April 26 (Box 175, Folder F.6)
        - "An Hour With the Secretary of State," 1962 November 28 (Box 175, Folder F.7)
        - "I.O.U. $315,000,000,000," 1966 March 15 (Box 175, Folder F.8)
        - "In Case of War," 1961 November 9 (Box 175, Folder F.9)
        - "Iran: Brittle Ally," 1961 December 18 (Box 175, Folder F.10)
        - "John Kennedy: The View from the Cabinet," 1963 December 18 (Box 175, Folder F.11)
        - "The Keeper of the Rules: Congressman Smith and the New Frontier," 1961 January 19 (Box 175, Folder F.12)
        - "The Legacy of the Thresher," 1964 March 4 (Box 175, Folder F.13)
        - "LSD: The Spring Grove Experiment," 1966 May 17 (Box 175, Folder F.14)
        - "The Man Who Built New York," 1963 April 17 (Box 175, Folder F.15)
        - "McNamara and the Pentagon," 1963 September 25 (Box 175, Folder F.16)
        - "Mexico: A Lesson in Latin," 1966 April 26 (Box 175, Folder F.17)
        - "Mississippi and the 15th Amendment," 1962 September 26 (Box 175, Folder F.18)
        - "Money and the Next President," 1960 October 27 (Box 175, Folder F.19)
        - "Mr. Europe and the Common Market," 1962 March 22 (Box 175, Folder F.20)
        - "Murder and the Right to Bear Arms," 1964 June 10 (Box 175, Folder F.21)
        - "New York Battleground: The Race for the Senate," 1964 October 21 (Box 175, Folder F.22)
        - "Nigeria: The Freedom Explosion," 1960 February 15 (Box 175, Folder F.23)
        - "The Other Face of Dixie," 1962 October 24 (Box 175, Folder F.24)
        - "Our Election Day Illusions: The Beat Majority," 1961 January 5 (Box 175, Folder F.25)
        - "The Policeman's Lot," 1966 March 29 (Box 176, Folder F.1)
        - "The Population Explosion," 1959 November 11 (Box 176, Folder F.2)
        - "The Press and the Law," 1965 January 181 (Box 176, Folder F.3)
        - "The Priest and the Politician," 1963 September 18 (Box 176, Folder F.4)
        - "The Rating Game," 1965 July 12 (Box 176, Folder F.5)
        - "A Real Case of Murder: The People vs. Peter Manceri," 1961 March 2 (Box 176, Folder F.6)
        - "Reflections of a Soviet Scientist," 1963 May 22 (Box 176, Folder F.7)
        - "Rescue with Yul Brynner," 1960 December 10 (Box 176, Folder F.8)
        - "Sabotage in South Africa," 1962 December 19 (Box 176, Folder F.9)
        - "Segregation: Northern Style," 1964 December 9 (Box 176, Folder F.10)
        - "The Selling of the Pentagon," 1971 March 23 (Box 176, Folder F.11)
        - "The Selling of the Pentagon: A Postscript," 1971 (Box 176, Folder F.12)
        - "The Selling of the Pentagon"--Summaries of Criticism, 1971 (Box 176, Folder F.13)
        - "Showdown in the Congo," 1962 October 3 (Box 176, Folder F.14)
        - "The Space Leg," 1960 January 6 (Box 176, Folder F.15)
        - "Storm Over the Supreme Court," 1963 (Box 176, Folder F.16)
        - "Story of a New Drug"--Research Material, 1963, (2 Folders) (Box 176, Folder F.17-18)
        - "The Taxed American," 1962 (Box 177, Folder F.1)
        - "The Teen-Age Smoker," 1962 September 19 (Box 177, Folder F.2)
        - "Three Presidents on the Presidency - Truman, Eisenhower, Kennedy," 1963 November 27 (Box 177, Folder F.3)
        - "Thunder on the Right," 1962 February 22 (Box 177, Folder F.4)
        - "The Trials of Charles de Gaulle," 1961 May 25 (Box 177, Folder F.5)
        - "Trujillo: Portrait of a Dictator," 1960 September 15 (Box 177, Folder F.6)
        - "UFO: Friend, Foe or Fantasy," 1966 May 10 (Box 177, Folder F.7)
        - "U.N.: Beleaguered Fortress," 1965 April 19 (Box 177, Folder F.8)
        - "The Uncounted Enemy: A Vietnam Deception," 1982, (2 Folders) (Box 177, Folder F.9)
        - "The U.S. and the Two Chinas," 1964 November 11 (Box 177, Folder F.10)
        - "Vietnam: The Deadly Decision," 1964 April 1 (Box 177, Folder F.11)
        - "Vietnam: The Other War," 1966 April 12 (Box 177, Folder F.12)
        - "The Volga," 1966 January 4 (Box 177, Folder F.13)
        - "Walter Lippmann on Leadership," 1960 August 11 (Box 177, Folder F.14)
        - "Walter Lippman, Year End," 1961 December 21 (Box 177, Folder F.15)
        - "Walter Lippman, Year End," 1961 December 21 (Box 178, Folder F.1)
        - "The War at the Top of the World," 1963 January 9 (Box 178, Folder F.2)
        - "The Water Famine," 1961 October 19 (Box 178, Folder F.3)
        - "Who Speaks for Birmingham?" 1961 May 18 (Box 178, Folder F.4)
        - "Who Speaks for the South?" 1960 May 27 (Box 178, Folder F.5)
        - "Why Man in Space?" 1961 April 27 (Box 178, Folder F.6)
        - "The Year of the Polaris," 1960 October 11 (Box 178, Folder F.7)
    - Edward R. Murrow, 1947-1991 (Box 179)
      - "Edward R. Murrow and the News" (CBS TV program)--Promotional Materials, 1947 (Box 179, Folder F.1)
      - Murrow's Address to the Radio and Television Network Directors Association, 1958 October 15 (Box 179, Folder F.4)
      - CBS Correspondence Concerning Murrow's Death, 1965 (Box 179, Folder F.5)
      - Editorials about Murrow's Death, 1965 April 27-28 (Box 179, Folder F.6)
      - Memorial Symposium, 1985-1991 (Box 179, Folder F.7)
      - Murrow: The Man Who Made the News (HBO film)--Promotional Packet and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 179, Folder F.8)
      - Prime Time: The Life of Edward R. Murrow, 1969 (Box 179, Folder F.9)
      - Good Night and Good Luck: An Evening with Edward R. Murrow by Joseph Vitale--Draft of Play, undated (Box 179, Folder F.11)
  - Subseries V.2: NBC Radio, 1948-1950
    Subseries V.2 contains scripts of two programs that Friendly wrote and directed while working as a radio producer for NBC; the quiz show Who Said That? and The Quick and the Dead, a documentary about the creation of the atomic bomb. It also includes a script of "Thinking Things Through," an interview with Richard Charles Rothschild.
    - Who Said That --Contract and Scripts, 1948-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder F.12-13)
    - The Quick and the Dead --Drafts and Scripts, 1950 July, (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder F.14-15)
    - Thinking Things Through --Transcript, 1950 September 15 (Box 179, Folder F.16)
  - Subseries V.3: PBS Television, 1968-1986
    This subseries is comprised of notes on funding for public television and transcripts for the PBS specials "Behind the Lines" and "The Whole World is Watching," as well as Why in the World, a public affairs program aimed at teenagers, which Friendly helped write and moderate.
    - Ethics and Funding for Public TV--Notes and Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 180, Folder F.1)
    - "The Whole World is Watching"--Transcript, 1968 December 22 (Box 180, Folder F.2)
    - "Behind the Lines"--Transcript, 1971 (Box 180, Folder F.3)
    - "Why in the World"--1984-1986 (Box 180, Folder F.4)
  - Subseries V.4: WEAN Radio, 1947
    This small subseries of material from Friendly's first radio job in Providence, Rhode Island contains scripts for several programs including Footprints in the Sands of Time, which he wrote and narrated.
    - Footprints on the Sands of Time --Transcripts, circa 1947 (Box 180, Folder F.5)
    - "Foreign Correspondent"--Transcript, circa 1947 (Box 180, Folder F.6)
    - "Gallup Poll of the Air"--Transcript and Notes, 1947, (2 Folders) (Box 180, Folder F.7-8)
    - Research Notes, circa 1947 (Box 180, Folder F.9)
- Series VI: General, 1934-2004
  - Subseries VI.1: Appointment Books and Phone Logs, 1961-1990
    While the entries in many of Friendly's appointment books and phone logs were sparse, these have been retained for their somewhat more detailed notes. They provide a glimpse at Friendly's busy day-to-day life and his many meetings with government officials and prominent members of the television and radio industries
    - Appointment Books
      - 1961 (Box 181, Folder F.1)
      - 1965 (Box 181, Folder F.2)
      - 1968 (Box 181, Folder F.3)
      - 1974 (Box 181, Folder F.4)
      - 1986 (Box 181, Folder F.5)
      - 1990 (Box 181, Folder F.6)
    - Phone Logs (Box 182)
      - 1981 May 19-1985 January 24, (10 notebooks) (Box 182, Folder F.1-10)
      - 1985 January 5-1987 August 6, (8 notebooks) (Box 183, Folder F.1-8)
      - 1987 August 7-1989 October 21, (9 notebooks) (Box 184, Folder F.1-9)
  - Subseries VI.2: Awards, 1967-1997
    This subseries documents some of the many awards Friendly received throughout his career. Also included is information on the Fred Friendly First Amendment Award at Quinnipiac College and its recipients. Documents include invitations, programs, clippings, correspondence, and some photographs. Files are arranged alphabetically by award title or awarding institution.
    - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences--Hall of Fame Inductee, 1994 (Box 185, Folder F.1)
    - Alfred I. DuPont Columbia University Awards, 1993-1994 (Box 185, Folder F.2)
    - American Bar Association--Silver Gavel Medal, 1992 and 1982 (Box 185, Folder F.3)
    - American Judicature Society--Justice Award, 1985 (Box 185, Folder F.4)
    - Anti Defamation League of B'nai Brith--Hubert H Humphrey First Amendment Freedom Prize, 1988 (Box 185, Folder F.5)
    - Barnard Medal of Distinction, 1992 May 12 (Box 185, Folder F.6)
    - Brown University Commencement - Honorary Degree, 1985 (Box 185, Folder F.7)
    - Columbia University--Honorary Degree, 1986 (Box 185, Folder F.8)
    - Columbia University, Teachers College--Medal for Distinguished Service, 1995 (Box 186, Folder F.1)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists--Burton Benjamin Memorial Award, 1997 (Box 186, Folder F.2)
    - Creative Arts Rehabilitation Center Awards Dinner--Public Spirit Award (Box 186, Folder F.3)
    - Distinguished Achievement in Journalism Dinner-University of Southern California, 1989 (Box 186, Folder F.4)
    - Friendly Hall Centennial Celebration-University of Oregon, 1993 (Box 186, Folder F.5)
    - Grinnell College Convocation--Honorary Degree, 1967 (Box 186, Folder F.6)
    - International Documentary Association - Career Achievement 1986 (Box 186, Folder F.7)
    - International Press Freedom--Awards Dinner, 1997 (Box 186, Folder F.8)
    - John Peter Zenger Award--University of Arizona, 1982 (Box 186, Folder F.9)
    - Lab School of Washington--Outstanding Disabled Achievers 1989 (Box 186, Folder F.10)
    - Libel Defense Resource Center--William J. Brennan Jr. Defense of Freedom Awards, 1997 (Box 186, Folder F.11)
    - Lowell Thomas Centennial Awards, 1992 (Box 186, Folder F.12)
    - National Broadcast Editorial Association's Madison Award, 1982 (Box 186, Folder F.13)
    - National Press Foundation--Awards Dinner, 1988 (Box 186, Folder F.14)
    - New Jersey State Bar Foundation Awards Dinner, 1992 (Box 187, Folder F.1)
    - New York Law School--Honorary Degree, 1987 (Box 187, Folder F.2)
    - Polk Awards, 1991 (Box 187, Folder F.3)
    - Quinnipiac College--First Amendment Award, 1994 (Box 187, Folder F.4)
    - Riverdale Mental Health Association Ball Honoring Fred and Ruth Friendly, 1987 (Box 187, Folder F.5)
    - RTNPA Paul White Award, 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 187, Folder F.6-7)
    - The Society of the Silurians Honors Fred W Friendly, 1983 (Box 187, Folder F.8)
    - Thomas Paine Award, 1990 and 1991 (Box 187, Folder F.9)
    - United State Holocaust Memorial Liberators Tribute, 1993 (Box 187, Folder F.10)
    - University of Utah Department of Communication--Service to Journalism Award, 1986 (Box 188, Folder F.1)
    - University of Wisconsin--Honorary Degree, 1970 (Box 188, Folder F.2)
    - Washington and Lee University--First Amendment Dinner, 1990 (Box 188, Folder F.3)
    - William O. Douglas Award, 1990 (Box 188, Folder F.4)
    - Women's American ORT Humanitarian Award, 1993 (Box 188, Folder F.5)
    - College of Wooster--Honorary Degree, 1982 (Box 188, Folder F.6)
  - Subseries VI.3: Columbia University, 1968-2002